谢谢，我今天要讲的是如何在浏览器中构建一个实用的所见即所得
Thank you, what I am going to talk about here today is how to build a robust WYSIWYM editor
编辑器。
in the browser.
所见即所得，我们通常的意思是
By what you see is what you mean, we usually mean something like
所见即所得，您可以直观地展示您的内容，并且可以以
get, WYSIWYG where you have a visual representation of your content and can just edit that in the
明显的光标选择方式对其进行编辑，而不是编辑
obvious classical way of cursor and selection, but instead of editing things like
字体之类的东西 大小边距这些信息，因此您可以对
font size margins of your editing semantic information so you get reduced cleaner representation
文档有更清晰的表示，您说这是一个段落，这是一个链接，而不是格鲁吉亚 15
of the document where you say this is a paragraph,this is a link, and not this is Georgia 15
像素斜体。
pixels italic.
当您想让用户编辑内容，然后您
This is usually beneficial when you want to have users edit content and you then later
想在不同的上下文中以不同的布局使用它，或者您想检查它
want to use it in a different layout in a different context or you want to inspect it,
并以某种方式对其进行转换时，这通常就很有用了，拥有相关的语义化信息比
and transform it somehow, it's very useful to have semantic information about the content
仅仅是布局信息有用多了。
rather than just layout information.
所以，我的最新项目叫做 ProseMirror。 我会说到 CodeMirror
So, my newest project is called ProseMirror. I am going to be talking about CodeMirror
和 ProseMirror。你不应该混淆它们， CodeMirror 是一个代码编辑器
and ProseMirror. You shouldn't confuse them, CodeMirror is a code editor
ProseMirror 是一个语义化的富文本编辑器，有点像所见即所得，但内容干净。
ProseMirror is a semantic rich text editor, so something like a WYSIWYG but for clean content.
这是最近推出并开源的，我尝试构建这么一个编辑器
This was recently launched and open sourced and it's my attempt to build an editor where
使您可以用它为您的内容定义范式并让编辑器自动执行该操作
you can define a schema for you content and have the editor automatically enforce that
并为用户提供在您的范式规则内的编辑操作，例如，如果您有
and provide the user with editing actions that stay within your schema so if you have
Github 你有你的文档模型，其中包括对 Issues 和
for example your Github you have you document model that includes references to issues and
commits 的引用。你可以扩展你的文档模型来拥有第一个子句，现在它是 commit 的
commits you can extend your document model to have first clause. Now it's links to commits
链接或用户的链接或其他任何东西，并且你的用户实际上正在使用对应的数据模型
or links to users or whatever and have your users actually be working with a data model
你真正想要使用的东西。
that corresponds to what you actually wantto work with.
ProseMirror 还支持协同编辑，因为我对未来
ProseMirror also supports collaborative editing and is generally I hope the future of in-browser
在浏览器上写作很有信心。
prose writing.
所以是的，我将会谈谈它是如何实现的
So yeah I am going to be talking about how it's implemented
大部分的富文本编辑器实现的一个主要因素是名为 contentEditable 的浏览器 API。
a major factor in any kind of rich text editing implementation is the browser API called contentEditable.
这是许多浏览器的所见即所得编辑器存在的原因
This is what enables many browser almost or in-browser WYSIWYGs to exist at all
如果您与使用它的人交谈，您会听到抱怨和许多可怕的故事
If you talk to people who have worked with it you will get complaints and lots of horrible stories
那么让我来介绍一些背景历史
So let me give a bit of background history
这一年是 1979 年，微软在浏览器方面进展顺利，他们只是移植了
The year is 1979, Microsoft is on a roll when it comes to browser they just ported
JavaScript，引入了动态 DOM 操作，然后我真的不知道发生了什么
JavaScript, introduced dynamic DOM manipulation. And then I guess I don't really know what happened
但假设那时有人说让我们制作我们的浏览器和编辑器，这样人们就可以
but assume someone there said let's make our browser and editor so people can write HTML
在浏览器中编写 HTML 。这是一个非常值得称道的想法。
in the browser. And this is a very commendable idea definitely
他们最终在 IE 4 中所做的是引入了一个名为 designMode 的功能
What they ended up doing in IE 4 is introducing a feature called designMode
这是在 document 上设置的一个属性，它使整个文档可编辑
It's a property you set on your document which makes the whole document editable
但是它的含义仍然不是很清楚， 没有涵盖此属性的规范你可以输入它 你可以退格
But what it means is still not clear. there's no spec that covers this you can type into it you can back space
基本上，你会得到一个光标和一个选区，你可以在其中打字，可以退格
Basically you get a cursor and a selection and you can type into it you can back space
和这个 API 的搭配的是 document.execCommand，您的脚本可以将字符串
And a companion to this API is document.execCommand which your scripts can parse string
转变为粗体、斜体或插入、删除有序列表或者对文档执行其他编辑操作
like bold or italic or insert ordered listor delete to perform other editing actions on the document
自从 IE 4 以来，您可以做的是建立一个框架，将其设置为可编辑
What you could do since IE 4 is create a frame, set it to be editable
然后绑定一些按键和按钮，以及各种执行命令代码，你就会有一个基本的所见即所得的编辑器
And then bind some key binding and buttons some various exec command codes you would have a basic WYSIWYG editor
这自 1997 年以来一直有效，然后在 2000 年，他们添加了第二个与之很像的功能，
This has worked since 1997, then in 2000 they added a second feature very similar to that
称为 contentEditable，和 designMode 一样，但针对的是每个 DOM 节点而不是整个文档
called contentEditable. This is the same as designMode but per DOM node instead of the whole document
意味着您不必创建 iFrame，只需在现有内容中设置开关
Meaning you don't have to create an iFrame. You can just in your existing content set the switch
以使其可编辑，让您的用户将某些内容添加到您的页面中，然后以某种方式保存它
to make it editable to let your users add something to a piece of your page then save it somehow
自从引入此功能以来，您还可以做的是将可编辑
Other important thing you could do since this feature was introduced was set pieces of an editable
DOM 节点的一部分设置为不可编辑，您可以在节点内部将其设置回 false
DOM node to be non editable you could set it back to false to be inside of the node,
这意味着用户可以很好地编辑文本，但他们无法将光标移动
that means that well the users can edit text round it but they can't move their cursor
到该节点并在那里开始编辑
into that node and start editing there
这也是一个很大的改进，它允许您保护文档的某些部分
This is also a big improvement, it allows you to protect some part of your document
或插入不一定可编辑的小部件
or insert widgets that are not necessarily editable
所以，这几乎是在 JavaScript 大繁荣之前的事了，人们慢慢开始使用它
So, this was pretty much before the big JavaScript boom but people were slowly starting to use
但在某个时候它变得非常广泛传播，CKEditor 应该是 2000 年代初期的
this at some point it become really wide spread, I think CKEditor is from the early 2000s
不确定 TinyMCE 何时开始，有一些使用这个 API 的库，人们会在内容管理系统中使用它们
not sure when TinyMCE started. There were libraries reping this and people using this to CMS
在 Mozilla ，我们有一种感觉，认为必须做这样的事情，这是一个有用的功能
At Mozilla there was a feeling we have todo something like this, it's a useful feature
但他们不太喜欢微软所做的，这是浏览器大战，所以
but they didn't quite like what Microsoft had done, and this was the browser war so
没有很好的标准规范沟通过程
it was not like there was a very good communication of standards process
他们花了一些时间试图提出一个更好的解决方案，但他们从未真正就某件事达成一致
They spent sometime trying to come up witha better solution but they never really agreed on something
所以最后他们说"好的"，我们只做了 Internet Explorer 所做的事情，这样我们就不再
So in the end they said ok we'll just do what Internet Explorer does so we're no longer
被排除在浏览器富文本编辑器之外
left out when it comes to rich text editor in browser with text editing
所以他们复制了这个功能，当然并没有完全复制它，他们的某些
So they copied this feature, of course it didn't exactly copy it they some parts of
部分没有用，他们忽略了这些部分，他们认为他们知道其他部分的更好解决方案
it were no use they left those out, they thought they knew better solutions for some other
例如，如果你将文字加粗，IE 会添加（听不清）文本，他们说不，我们上面
parts for example where IE would add &*% text if you made something bold, they said no we
有字体宽度的 CSS。
have CSS that font width on them.
我也不清楚为啥
I'm not sure why
在当时两个主要浏览器上都有该功能
You had the feature on both major browsers then and a few years later
直到 2007 年，在 JavaScript 热潮之后，Firefox 也添加了对 contentEditable 的支持
actually took until 2007 which is past the JavaScript boom that Firefox also added support for contentEditable
然后其他浏览器 Safari、Chrome、Opera 也都采用了该功能
and then the other browsers Safari, Chrome, Opera, all also took up the feature
并以一种或另一种方式实现它，现在它被认为是现代图形浏览器中预期 API 的一部分
and implemented it one way or another. And now it's kind of considered part of the expected API in a modern graphical browser
那么为什么这是一件好事呢？
So why is this a good thing?
我们必须在浏览器中实现编辑的其他控件是文本区域和文本
The other controls that we have to implementediting in a browser are text area and text \\TODO
输入。
input.
两者都受限于纯文本的原子块，你不能真正做很多
Both of which are constrained to atomic blobsof plain text you can't really do many of
你想用它们做的事情，比如在其中做富文本是一个非首发，甚至
the things you want to do with them like doingrich text in them is a non starter and even
添加一些有用的小部件或语法突出显示几乎是不可能的 在文本区域顶部执行
adding some helpful widgets or syntax highlightingis almost impossible to do on top of text
。
area.
所以很好的是，我们有一个替代方案，我们可以在浏览器中进行可靠的富文本编辑
So it's great then we have an alternativethat we can do solid rich text editing or
或或多或少可靠的富文本编辑，例如
more or less solid rich text editing in abrowser, things like content management systems
完全在线存在的内容管理系统，早期的代码编辑器也基于此。
that exist entirely online, earlier code editorswere also based on this.
这太棒了。
This is wonderful.
当然，除了它有问题之外，HTML 范围并不大，你可能
Except of course, it has problems a majorthing HTML scope is not gigantic, you might
不想要整个范围，例如，CodeMirror 的第一个版本基于 contentEditable
not want that whole scope for example, firstversion of CodeMirror it was based on contentEditable
图像将整个表格链接到编辑器中，我不得不以某种方式处理这个问题。
images links whole tables into the editorI had to somehow deal with this.
所以你可以过滤内容，无论如何你都想过滤内容，
So you can do that you can filter content,you properly want to filter the content anyway,
默认情况下它就是这样出来的，非常非常难看。
it comes out of this by default, it's very,very ugly.
因此，现代 WYSIWYG 浏览器具有相当先进的机制来清除
So that modern WYSIWYG browsers have prettyadvanced mechanisms for cleaning out the HTML
编辑器内部的 HTML，但是仍然存在所有浏览器差异，
inside of the editor, but then there's stillall the browser differences, there's no spec,
每个浏览器都没有规范。
each browser.
这是编辑 HTML 真正含义的一个非常大的范围，光标在
This is a very big scope of what editing HTMLreally means, there's cursor motion through
表格中移动，向表格中添加列，当您在定义列表中显示输入时会发生
tables, adding columns to table, what happenswhen you present enter in a definition list,
什么，如果光标跨块元素的边界移动，光标位置到底是什么，
what exactly is the cursor position if it'smoving across the boundaries of block elements,
什么是有效的光标位置。
what is a valid cursor position.
这些都是有效的问题，他们给出的答案略有不同。
These are all valid questions, they came upwith slightly different answers to them.
然后是错误。
Then there's bugs.
许多
Many
错误。
bugs.
我得到的感觉是，除了少数启动
The feeling I get is that no-one really maybeexcept for the few engineers that started
这个东西的工程师之外，没有人真的可能想要实现这个，但这是需要和
this thing, no-one really felt like implementingthis but it was something that is needed and
预期的东西，所以所有浏览器供应商都不得不以某种方式宣传这条龙 一个子浏览
expected and so all the browser vendors hadto somehow ad this dragon of a sub browser
器以各种可怕的方式与所有东西交互，多年来一直存在语言错误和错误
that interacted with everything in all kindsof horrible ways, bugs with language and bug
跟踪器，似乎没有人真正关心那么多。
trackers for years an years it seems no-onereally cared all that much.
这种情况最近有所改善，目前在现代浏览器上，您确实可以
The situation has recently improved, currentlyon modern browsers you can really make some
对用户编辑 HTML 时会发生什么做出一些假设，以前
assumptions about what is going to happento your HTML as the user is editing it, didn't
在 CodeMirror 1 中并非如此，我只是一堆堆
used to be the case in CodeMirror 1, I havejust piles and piles of workarounds to deal
解决所有这些奇怪问题的解决方法。
with all these weird issues.
它只是一个文本编辑器，如果你真的支持丰富的内容，那就更糟了。
It was only a text editor, it will be a lotworse if you actually support rich content.
所以，人们对此真的很恼火，然后有一代编辑，
So, people really got annoyed with this andthen there is a generation of editors, it
从代码编辑开始，他们只是说，“好吧，我们根本不打算碰这个，我们会
started with code editors, who just say, "Ok,we're not going to touch this at all, we'll
自己想办法，我们 实现一切，所以我们实现了我们自己的选择，
figure something out ourselves, we implementeverything, so we implement our own selection,
只是 DOM 实际上是不可编辑的，我们通过捕获事件并更改
just the DOM is not actually editable, wepretend it is by capturing events and changing
您在屏幕上看到的文档来响应这些事件来假装它是可编辑的。”
your documents you see on the screen in responseto these events."
第一个实现这一点的是 Ace代码编辑器，那时我还在
The first one to pull this off was the Acecode editor at that point I was still messing
自己的代码编辑中搞乱 contentEditable，我认为这显然更优越，
about with contentEditable in my own codeediting, I thought ok this is clearly superior,
我只是放弃了内容编辑器，再也没有回去。
I just dropped content editor and never wentback.
谷歌文档，使用这个，你看到的绿色闪烁是一个隐藏并定期显示的小 gif
Google docs, uses this, what you see blinkingon the green is a little gif that's hidden
，你可以很远，在桌面浏览器上，你可以使用这种技术获得良好的编辑
and shown periodically, you can very far,on desk top browsers you can get a good editing
体验。
experience using this technique.
在某些时候你确实会遇到问题，如果你完全保持自己的选择，
At some point you do run into problems, ifyou maintain your own selection entirely,
你会得到你盘子上双向文本的所有复杂性，你必须
you get all the complexity of bi directionaltext on your plate you have to implement what
实现光标应该做的事情，如果它从右到左移动，那么 输入从左到右的
the cursor is supposed to be doing, if itmoves right to left, then enters left to right
文本，有一个岛...
text and there is an island of... if you aremixing Arabic or Hebrew or other scripts you
-
get islands inside of your paragraphs thatare running in different directions, people
need like this.
就像阿拉伯语或希伯来语作家真的需要它来工作一样，如果它不起作用，你就不能对你的编辑器做太多事情，把
Like Arabic or Hebrew writers really needthis to be work, you can't do much with your
它做好是非常困难的。
editor if it doesn't work, it's giganticallydifficult to get it right.
内容菜单应该显示剪切和粘贴，如果您单击它，如果那里有不可编辑的
The content menu should shows cut and paste,if you click on it, if you have a non-editable
gif，它不会知道。
gif there, it won't know.
你可以找到这个的十六进制，这个的十六进制是
You can find the hex for this, the hex forthis is to pop-up a tiny transparent text
当用户右键单击并在剪切或粘贴时挂钩正确的东西时，在光标下弹出一个微小的透明文本区域
area under the cursor when the user rightclicks and hooks up the right thing when he
，你可以让它工作，但它的 痛苦或尴尬。
cuts or pastes, you can get it to work butit's painful or awkward.
然后，移动界面，触摸界面变得普遍，并且
Then, mobile interfaces, touch interfacesbecame widespread and the integration Between
选择和触摸界面之间的集成非常深刻和微妙，产生了原生选择，当你实际上不让浏览器知道选择时，
the selection and touch interface is verydeep and very subtle, producing a native selection,
一个原生字段来操作
a native field to manipulate the selectionwhen you are not actually letting the browser
选择是 几乎不可能，我认为还没有人成功。
know about the selection is almost impossible,I don't think anyone has pulled it off yet.
所以这也可能不是正确的解决方案。
So this may not be the right solution either.
所以也许让我们在中间见面，这就是促使 ProseMirror 的想法，
So maybe let's meet in the middle and thisis the idea that prompted ProseMirror, give
给编辑器可见的 DOM，当用户做某事并生成一个事件时，
the editor the visible DOM, when the userdoes something and it generates an event,
我们介入并说做任何事情浏览器，我们会处理这个并且 get - 将它与
we step in and say doing do anything browser,we'll handle this and get - isolate this from
contentEditable 的许多恐怖隔离开来，不再发生 DOM 的随机操作
a lot of the horrors of contentEditable, therandom manipulation by the DOM is no longer
，它允许我们定义模型并且是
happens, it allows us to define the modeland be the
唯一接触到的人，在旧方法中，DOM 是您的文档模型。
only one touching that, in the older approachthe DOM is your document model.
您不保留自己的数据副本，让 DOM 确定文档的
You don't keep your own copy of the data youlet the DOM determine what the document looks
外观，您不知道浏览器将对此做什么，这就像在流沙上构建，
like, you don't know what the browser willdo with this, it's like building on quicksand,
事情可能会发生变化，请注意您以某种方式依赖 现有的可能会
things might change, notes that you somehowdepending on existing might be replaced by
被副本取代，完全控制提供您的文档模型是一件非常有用的事情，我
a copy, having full control offer your documentmodel is a very useful thing to do and I think
认为最近出现的其他一些所见即所得也朝着这个方向发展。
some of the other WYSIWYGs that have croppedup recently are also moving in this direction.
.
是的，ProseMirror 是从头开始设计的，假设我们有一个文档
Yeah, ProseMirror is designed from the groundup with the assumption that we have a document
模型，然后有一个 DOM，DOM 是文档模型上的一个视图，文档
model and then there is a DOM, the DOM isa view on the document model, the document
是实体的，我们完全拥有它，当它发生变化时，我们会更新 DOM 自己并向
is solid we have it entirely, when it's changedwe update the DOM ourselves and show the user
用户显示伪可编辑的东西，它应该是可编辑的，但我们不让他们直接编辑
the pseudo editable thing, it's supposed tobe editable but we don't let them edict directly,
，选择不是您可以在触摸界面上操作的真实选择，
the selection is not a real selection youcan manipulate on a touch interface, bi directional
双向文本的双向光标移动可以通过浏览器离开，我们想
cursor motion by bi directional text can beleft through the browser, we dent want to
考虑一下，这样可以节省复杂性。
think about that, that saves complexity.
当然，实现我们自己的文档模型和所有可能的更改也是非常
Of course implementing our own document modeland all possible changes is also a lot of
复杂的，但我认为这是您作为文本编辑器想要的复杂性，您希望
complexity, but this is complexity I thinkyou want as a text editor, you want to define
以一种可预测的、明确定义的方式来定义它。
it in one predictable, well-defined way.
你想让它们可定制，你想在涉及到的时候去掉浏览器。
You want to make them customisable, you wantto cut out the browser when it comes to that.
因此，我将稍微介绍一下 ProseMirror 文档模型，三个基础很像
So I'm going to go into ProseMirror documentmodel for a bit, three base much like the
DOM，如果您有一个包含三个项目列表的文档，它看起来像这样。
DOM, if you have a document with a list ofthree items, it looks something like this.
您现在得到一个列表或三个项目注释，其中包含一些文本内容的段落注释。
You get a list now or three item notes, paragraphnotes with some text content in it.
它与 DOM 完全不同的一件事是它是一个持久数据结构，
One thing that it does very differently fromthe DOM it's a persistent data structure,
所以如果你更新它，你会创建一个新版本，而旧版本不会受到影响，所以你只是
so if you update it you create a new versionand the old version is untouched, so you just
不去那里开始添加孩子，我不 不知道在哪里。
don't go in there and start adding children,I don't know where.
有一组明确定义的可能更新，您可以应用更新来获取新文档。
There is a well-defined set of possible updatesand you apply an update to get a new document.
这并不像听起来那么昂贵，如果您在此列表中添加一个项目，它可以进行数据共享
This is not as expensive as it sounds, itcan do data sharing if you an item to this
，您只需重复使用旧项目注释并复制文档和列表
list here, you just reuse the old item notesand make a copy of the document and the list
注释，列表注释中的第四个孩子，您只是在复制两个笔记，而
notes, the fourth child in the list notes,you are only copying two notes rather than
不是整个文档结构。
your whole document structure.
ProseMirror 所做的另一件事与 DOM 不同，当您有行内内容时，
Another thing that ProseMirror does differentlyfrom the DOM, when you have in line content
这就是您如何表示带有蜜蜂链接和注释文本的段落，您创建
this is how you represent a paragraph witha bees of link and note text in it, you create
一个带有例如强注释的子树，然后将内容放在 强下那。
a subtree with for example a strong note andyou put the content that's strong under that.
ProseMirror 实际上是线性的，其中行内的段落内容始终是
ProseMirror actually makes linear, where inline paragraph content is always a sequence
带有样式信息和图像或注释的文本序列，它们可以出现在这里，
of pieces of text with styling informationand images or notes that can appear here,
它们不嵌套，超出段落级别没有嵌套，您可以看到这是怎么回事
they don't nest, beyond the paragraph levelthere is no nesting you can see how this is
比这更难读。
harder to read than this.
当你在代码中处理它时也是一样的，很多你想做的事情
It's the same when you are dealing with itin code, a lot of the things you want to do
在这方面要容易得多，例如，验证你没有两次强调一段文本
are much easier on this, for example, verifyingthat you are not emphasising a piece of text
，这是微不足道的，这个树表示是一个 树表示的痛苦类似地，
twice, it's trivial and this tree representationis a pain in the... tree representation similarly
如果我们想表示段落中的位置，我们可以只是一个字符偏移量，我们
if we want to represent positions in the paragraphwe can just a character offset and we
不必担心树关系。
don't have to worry about tree relations.
所以这是一个巨大的胜利，让定义很多东西变得更容易。
So this was a big win and made it easier todefine a lot of things.
那么让我们看看当 ProseMirror 捕获事件时会发生什么。
So let's see what happens when ProseMirrorcaptures events.
你有你的编辑器，它渲染了一段可编辑的 DOM，对应于
You have your editor, it's rendered a pieceof editable DOM corresponding to the document
它在内存软件中的文档，有人按下“A”，我们为此捕获一个事件
it has itself in memory software, and someonepresses 'A', we capture an event for that
并创建一个更改对象。
and create a change object.
ProseMirror 中的更改是您可以存储和传递的一流对象，我们
Changes in ProseMirror are first class objectswhich you can store and pass around and we'll
稍后再讨论。
come back to that later.
然后我们将更改对象应用于我们当前的文档，获取新文档，
Then we apply the change object to our currentdocuments, get the new documents, make that
制作当前文档并安排 DOM 更新，类似地，如果您按“退格”，您只需
the current documents and schedule a DOM update,similarly if you press 'Backspace', you just
使用退格计算要删除的内容，创建更改 ，获取
compute what you want to be deleting withbackspace, create a change, take the content
剪贴板的内容，将其传递到我们的文档格式中，并用这个文档片段替换选择，
of the clipboard, pass it into our documentformat and replace the selection with this
以获得另一个更改对象。
document fragment to get another change object.
然后通过更新 DOM 来完成，因为我使用请求信息框架安排更新
Updating the DOM is then done by, as I schedulingupdates using request information frames,
，下次浏览器进行实际重绘时，它将首先运行代码，
the next time the browser does an actual redrawit will first run are code which is responsible
负责确保 DOM 反映当前文档关于持久性的好处
for making sure the DOM reflects the currentdocument the nice thing about the persistent
停靠搜索我们可以做很多反应，我们可以将文档与当前文档分开，
dock searches we can do pretty much react,we can div the document with the current document
并仅对DOM 进行必要的更改以移动到新文档，这
and make the changes only that are necessaryto the DOM to move to the new document, this
是非常高效和快速的，我们只需要做一点 比较，好的，这里没有任何变化
is insanely efficient and fast, we can justdo one point to compare, ok, nothing changed
，继续下一个音符。
here and move on to the next note.
当然它并不完全完美，在某些情况下解析不会触发好的事件， - 你
Of course it's not entirely perfect, in somecases parses do not fire good events, - you
写点击并选择这个世界的另一种拼写，然后它只会修改 DOM
write click and choose another spelling ofthis world, then it will just modify the DOM
然后说，“输入”，意思是改变了，你不要 对此一无所知。
and then say, "Input", meaning something changed,you don't know anything about it.
所以，我们必须处理这个问题，在这种情况下，我们只需要 DOM 的一部分，比如
So, we have to deal with that and in thiscase we just take the part of the DOM, like
光标周围的块元素，重新解析它们，根据我们
the block elements around the cursor, reparsethose, div those with our understanding of
对文档的这些部分的外观的理解来划分它们并进行更改 从那开始，幸运的是，
what those parts of that document look likeand arrive at change from that, fortunately
我只是在简单的文本更改中遇到了这个问题，并且派生一个简单的文本
I've only run into this problem for simpletextual changes and deriving a simple text
更改是安全的，那里不会发生任何奇怪的事情，到目前为止这运作良好我仍然希望
change is safe, nothing weird can happen there,so far this is working well I'm still expecting
在某个时候遇到更多问题 这里。
at some point to run into more problems here.
因此，让所有这些持久对象以一种很好的价值方式表示一切，我们可以定义
So, having all these persistent objects representingeverything in a nice value way, we can define
一种更改代数，基本操作是将更改应用于文档。
a kind of algebra of changes, the basic operationis applying the change to a document.
在这里，我们有一个蓝色的东西代表一个文档，一个橙色的东西代表一个变化，我们应用
Here we have a blue thing for a document andan orange thing for a change and we apply
它来获取一个新的文档，在这种情况下，我们删除字符集 2 和 8 之间的第 0 段中的部分
that getting a new document, in this casewe delete the part in 0 paragraph between
，我们得到一个新的文档对象和 也是一张地图。
character off set 2 and 8, we get a new documentobject and also a map.
地图是位置地图，它是一种将文档更改前版本中的
A map is a position map, it's a way to associatepositions in the pre-change version of the
位置与更改后文档中的位置相关联的方法，在这种情况下，我们可以查询此地图
document with positions in the post changedocument, in this case we can query this map
以询问光标在第一段中位置 11 的位置 旧文档，
to ask cursor position in the first paragraphat position 11 in the old document, where
新文档中的这个在哪里。
is this in the new document.
它会说，“它的位置是 05”，意思是第一个字符中的第五个字符......这
It will say, "It's positioned 05", meaningthe fifth character in the first... this is
主要用于使光标随着文档的变化而移动，所以它不应该
mainly used for making the cursor move asthe document changes, so it shouldn't jump
跳来跳去，而是保持在它的位置。
around but stay in its position.
你可以
There is a bunch of nice things you can
用它做很多好事，比如检查你刚刚
do with this, like checking pieces of thedocument you just create two positions in
在文档中围绕你感兴趣的部分创建两个位置的文档片段，你不断将它们映射到新文档
the document around the part you are interestedin, you keep mapping those to the new document
，你最终知道在哪里 您正在检查的文本结束了，它
and you end up knowing where the text youare checking ended up, it's also essential
对于协作编辑也是必不可少的，它允许我们通过映射与更改对象关联的位置
for collaborative editing, it allows us bymapping the positions associated with the
来将更改从一个文档移动到该文档的另一个版本。
change object to move changes from one documentto another version of that document.
因此，例如，如果我们在删除操作之外还有另一个更改对象说
So, for example, if we had beyond this deleteoperation we had another change object saying,
“在位置 11 处插入一个字符”，我们现在可以说相同的更改但应用于
"Insert a character at position 11", we cannow say that same change but applied to the
第二个文档是，在位置 5 处插入相同的字符 ，因此，如果您
second document is, insert the same characterat position 5, so if you have a collaborative
设置了协作编辑并且两个用户同时进行，则其中一个最终会先进行，
editing set up and two users make it concurrently,one of them will end up going first and the
另一个将具有他们所做的更改，但他们无法
other one will have this change that theyhave made, but that they're not able to apply
应用于当前 文件，因为文件在此期间发生了变化。
to the current document because the documentchanged in the meantime.
他们可以使用这种方法来获取其他用户所做的更改，移动他们自己的更改，
They can use this approach to take the changethat the other user made, move their own changeover
然后应用它并重新尝试将其推送到服务器，所以它有点像，到达
it and then apply it and retry pushing itto the server, so it's kind of like, get to
基地，你尝试推送，你得到一个 冲突，你尝试在本地rebase，然后你尝试
base, you try to push, you get a conflict,you try to rebase locally and then you try
再次repush，效果很好，实际上有很多，你可以
to repush again, it works quite well, thereis quite a bit to it actually, you can find
在我的博客上找到很长的歧视，效果很好，比较简单和可靠
a long discrimination on my blog, it worksquite well, it's a relatively simple and solid
进行协作编辑的方式。
way to do collaborative editing.
这有更多的应用，比如更改跟踪，如果您只是保留所有更改的历史记录
There is more applications of this, say changetracking, if you just keep a history of all
，您总是可以找出文档的来源，
your changes, you can always find out wherea piece of the document originated, stuff
诸如此类。
like that.
我敢肯定还有更多，我们还没有真正探索到这一步，但这是一个不错的
I'm sure there is more, we haven't reallyexplored this far yet, but it's a nice place
地方，很好的基础。
to, nice basis to build on.
然后我想，很简单的谈一下未来。
Then I want to, very briefly talk about thefuture.
因此，W 3 C 正在对此 contentEditable 标准进行更新，这将允许
So, the W 3 C is working on an update to thiscontentEditable standard which would allow
一种新的 contentEditable 模式，您应该这样做，
a new mode of contentEditable, where you aresupposed to do exactly this, the document
文档不可编辑，您应该捕获事件并编辑库存 你自己，那么
isn't editable, you are supposed to captureevents and edit the inventory yourself, then
他们还必须为
they will also have to define a few more eventsfor stuff like the spell checking issue that
我之前展示的拼写检查问题和更多类似的东西定义更多事件，但是是的，那会很好，因为它
I showed before and a bunch more like this,but yeah, that would be nice because it relives
让浏览器供应商重新维护了整个可怕的 blob 代码，它让编辑器
the browser vendors of maintaining this wholehorrible blob of code and it gives editor
实现者了解如何实现一个健壮的实体编辑器，而不会
implementers a view of how to implement arobust solid editor, without going insane
在这个过程中发疯。
in the process.
当然，你永远不知道 W 3 C 标准什么时候会真正出现在浏览器中，但
Of course, you never know when W 3 C standardwill actually end up in browsers, but I'm
我听说浏览器对此很感兴趣，可能出于我提到的原因，
told that browsers are enthusiastic aboutthis, probably for the reasons I mentioned,
它可能会发生，但规范还没有完成 然而，这可能会很
it will probably be happening, but the specificationisn't finished yet, it will probably be a
长一段时间。
long time.
这是 URL，ProseMirror.net 和Github.com/ProseMirror。
This is the URLs, the ProseMirror.net andGithub.com/ProseMirror.
随意使用它，它还没有完成，但它可以按原样工作，主要
Feel free to play with it, it's not finishedyet but it works as it is, the major big thing
需要改进的是 API 或语言，用于定义您自己的文档方案
that has to improve is the API or languagefor defining your own document schemers and
并灵活处理您在文档中可能需要的所有内容 策划者。
having flexible for all the things you mightwant in your document schemer.
我们将于周一在柏林就这个项目举行一次见面会，如果您认为您
We are having a meet up on Monday around thisproject here in Berlin, if you think you might
可能感兴趣，请前往讨论。ProseMirror.net，一个讨论论坛，其中一个主题是
be interested, go to discuss.ProseMirror.net,a discussion forum and one of the topics is
这次
this
见面，欢迎您申请 出色地。
meet up, you are welcome to apply as well.
就是这样，谢谢你的收听。
That's it, thank you for listening.